shoppingandbuying.com 2011-10-04

# Privacy Policy

ShoppingandBuying.com would like to provide you with the following Statement of Privacy.  This Privacy Policy explains how ShoppingandBuying.com utilizes your information while taking measures to secure your privacy.

Any further use of ShoppingandBuying.com constitutes an agreement between you and the website.  You agree to the ShoppingandBuying.com terms and conditions listed in the User Agreement, which includes this Privacy Policy and consent to the privacy practices of the ShoppingandBuying.com Network.  Keep in mind that this includes any use or disclosure of your personal information that you willingly shared with ShoppingandBuying.com and its storage on ShoppingandBuying.com servers within the United States. 

## **Disclosure of Personal Information**

Personal information is not required in order to browse the ShoppingandBuying.com Network.  The only time personal information is requested is in the event that you would like to take part in one of the services we offer or take advantage of a special feature.  This information is basic and only required so that ShoppingandBuying.com can identify you.    
Certain information will be collected automatically from your computer as you browse ShoppingandBuying.com websites.  The information that is automatically extracted includes IP addresses, browser information, connection and computer details, operating system and platform type, URL details and a cookie number 

In order to register with ShoppingandBuying.com an email address and password must be provided.  A feature of ShoppingandBuying.com is the ability to share your information with other users.  If you choose to create a member profile you will be asked to share information such as your first and last name, a member login name and location, your profile preferences and other information that always us to personalize your user experience.  At time fulfillment information will be required like your mailing address and phone number.  You may chose to not disclose this information, but it will inhibit the benefits of full activity on the ShoppingandBuying.com website.

In specific cases additional information may be requested from you.  If you contact customer support for example, we will need some information from you in order to answer your questions or solve any issue you might have.  Other cases where additional information may be required include survey participation or if ShoppingandBuying.com receives a complaint about your usage of our website by a third-party. 

## **ShoppingandBuying & Co-Branded Services **

ShoppingandBuying.com would like to ensure that all of our users have the best experience possible when utilizing our websites.  In order to provide our users with a complete and fulfilling experience, ShoppingandBuying.com utilizes third-party websites in order to offer co-branded services.  Be aware that when you leave ShoppingandBuying.com to browse a co-branded website, you are subject to the terms and conditions of that website and no longer under the protection of ShoppingandBuying.com.  The information provided on a third-party website will not be shared with ShoppingandBuying.com.  How will you know that you have left ShoppingandBuying.com and entered a third-party website?  Look for the logo.  The logo of any website outside of the ShoppingandBuying network will appear at the top of the page. 

## **Utilizing Personal Information**

Your information will be used to resolve disputes, troubleshoot any technical problems and address any of your complaints.  Your personal information helps us determine what promotional offers and advertisements you would be interested in.  In order to be effective at communication your information is required so that we can provide you with prompt feedback and the services you have requested.  In order to analyze our website, monitor user behavior and prepare reports your information is helpful.  Lastly, your information helps us measure and improve our services and website in general.

## **Disclosure**

In cases where joint services are required your personal information may be shared with our parent company, joint ventures, subsidiaries or other companies under common control with ShoppingandBuying.com.  At times ShoppingandBuying.com will need to provide internal statistics, make strategic decisions, share customer reviews, identify consumer trends, verify a customer, prevent fraud or provide security and at those times your information may be shared.  Service providers help ShoppingandBuying.com maintain our network and provide related services, in certain cases we may share you information with service providers in order to maintain website functionality.

Special offers are fun and we would like you to take advantage of them.  In order to provide you with the services or products of a third-party website that you have expressed interest in or have requested, we will share your personal information. 

If you partake in a survey some of that information may be utilized in order to conduct market research and to assist in internal development.  Your results may be shared with our service providers, consultants, vendors or affiliates **.**

In the event that ShoppingandBuying.com must declare bankruptcy or in the event of a merger, the transfer or sale of assets may be required.  In that event personal information of ShoppingandBuying.com users may be one of the assets included.

At times the law may require that we divulge your personal information.  If ShoppingandBuying.com has a good-faith belief that this disclosure is necessary and required under applicable law,  will comply with requests made through the legal system, will protect the interests or property of ShoppingandBuying.com, our employees and agents or to protect the overall safety of the community, we may share your personal information. 

## **Reviews, Ratings & Comments**

Before you write a review, leave a comment or contribute a rating be aware that your content will be shared with the ShoppingandBuying.com Network and will appear to the public.  Your member name may be displayed along with your content and shared with the public.  Other ShoppingandBuying.com users have the ability to receive notifications via email when you post something new.  If you wish to change any of this please visit your profile settings or refrain from posting content.

The content you contribute to ShoppingandBuying.com helps us mark products, personalize site views and develop ratings.  Your reviews may be used in order to determine who are most popular reviewers are.  We will use the content you submit to generate results for other ShoppingandBuying.com members.

## **SPAM & Opting Out**

Administrative emails cannot be opted out of.  These emails are required notifications and keep you informed about your usage, Terms and Service and other agreements and policies between you and ShoppingandBuying.com.  All other emails can be opted out of.  Simply visit your preferences and choose to opt out of any email you wish to no longer receive.  
You have the option of emailing members of our website; however, you do not have our permission to send spam or any other content that violates our User Agreement or that would be found offensive to a ShoppingandBuying.com member.  Emails sent through ShoppingandBuying.com are not private communications and can be monitored.

ShoppingandBuying.com will not send emails at any time without permission; we will not sell or lend email address to an outside party.  We cannot prevent others from sending you spam, but if you believe that you have received spam from us contact our Privacy Department so that we can conduct a full investigation. 

## **Cookies anyone?**

Cookies are sometimes used by ShoppingandBuying.com and those who provide us with joint services, in order to monitor your use of our site in order to improve our services, recognize returning users, measure activity and traffic of our website and protect users against fraud.  Cookies can be easily blocked by changing your browser settings.  However, blocking cookies may prevent you from receiving the full benefits of our website including certain services.  For example, in order to register with the ShoppingandBuying.com Network your browser must accept cookies. Advertisers may also place cookies in order to create and provide you with targeted advertisements.

## **Updating and Editing Personal Information**

It is in your benefit to update your personal information.  If your contact information becomes inaccurate it can interfere in the fulfillment of requests made by you through ShoppingandBuying.com.  You can close your account with ShoppingandBuying.com at any time. Simply contact our customer support and a friendly representative will go through the steps with you. 

Some of your personal information may be stored in our databases in order to prevent fraud, resolve a dispute, troubleshoot and analyze programs, enforce our User Agreement, assist in an investigation, comply with the law or other actions permitted by law. 

## **Linked Accountability**

Other websites have been linked to ShoppingandBuying.com in order to provide you with products and services you may be interested in.  These sites are not operated by ShoppingandBuying.com and act independently.  We are not responsible for the practices of any website linked to the ShoppingandBuying.com Network.  Likewise, ShoppingandBuying.com cannot be held accountable for the content or images used on these websites.  If you have an issue with a third-party website or a concern about their terms or privacy policy, please make sure to contact that outside party.

## **Security Measures**

We restrict access to your personal information to the public but also within our staff.  Only employees who require your information in order to develop, improve or operate ShoppingandBuying.com services have access to it.  Our technicians have worked to develop a variety of safeguards that protect our databases and your passwords; however, we cannot guarantee that a party acting outside of the ShoppingandBuying.com network may illegally intercept or access private communications between you and our network.  In the case of an illegal interception we cannot guarantee your privacy. 

## **Amendments**

In order to keep up with user demands and make sure that ShoppingandBuying.com is always performing at a premium level, we must make changes to our websites and therefore adjust this Privacy Policy.  Please note that whenever changes have been made to this policy they will be posted to this page.  Amendments to this policy will not take effect until 30 days after they have been posted, those who register after amendments have been posted must agree to the new terms immediately.
